Music was his world. Then silence revealed a new one.
Sound of Metal is a drama, music film directed by Darius Marder.
Metal drummer Ruben begins to lose his hearing.
When a doctor tells him his condition will worsen, he
thinks his career and life is over.
His girlfriend Lou checks the former addict into a rehab for the deaf hoping
it will prevent a relapse and help him adapt to his new life.
After being welcomed and accepted just as he is, Ruben must choose
between his new normal and the life he once knew.
Ruben Stone, played by Riz Ahmed.
Lou, played by Olivia Cooke.
Joe, played by Paul Raci.
Diane, played by Lauren Ridloff.
Richard Berger, played by Mathieu Amalric.
Michael, played by Domenico Toledo.
Sound of Metal is a 2019 American drama film directed by Darius Marder, who co-wrote the story with
Derek Cianfrance before co-writing the screenplay with his brother Abraham Marder.
It stars Riz Ahmed as a metal drummer who loses his hearing.
The cast also includes Olivia Cooke, Paul Raci,
Lauren Ridloff, and Mathieu Amalric.
Sound of Metal had its world premiere in the Platform Prize program at the
2019 Toronto International Film Festival on September 6, 2019.
Amazon Studios released the film in theaters on November 20,
2020, and on Amazon Prime Video on December 4.
The film was critically acclaimed, with particular praise for the performances of
Ahmed and Raci, the sound design, the editing, direction, and screenplay.
It was listed on 52 film critics' top-ten lists for 2020.
At the 93rd Academy Awards, it was nominated for Best Picture, Best Original Screenplay, Best Actor
(Ahmed) and Best Supporting Actor (Raci), and won for Best Sound and Best Film Editing.
The film explores themes of deaf, missouri, drums, heavy metal, addiction.
The tone is emotional.